<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>kd goes 2 SG</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://kadie16.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://kadie16.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 01:20:16 +1000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 01:20:16 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Koh Phi Phi</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After I landed in Krabi, I made my way to Phi Phi island (pronounced pee-pee :)). Sarah and Ryan were waiting for me at the dock with a little paper sign that said “Ms. Jaffe”!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kadie16/kadie16.github.io/master/assets/images/posts/phi-phi/ferry.JPG&quot; /&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;center&gt;Phi Phi Arrival&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we walked through town to drop off my stuff at the bungalow (we like to call it the fungalow).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kadie16/kadie16.github.io/master/assets/images/posts/phi-phi/bungalowView.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;center&gt; View From The Fungalow &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later I had some pad thai for about 80 baht (under $3) and we went to sunset bar for some drinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kadie16/kadie16.github.io/master/assets/images/posts/phi-phi/sunsetBar.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;center&gt; Sunset Bar &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day, we had banana milk and sugar thai pancakes and banana shakes for breakfast, at what would become my favorite resturaunt on phi phi. There are a ton of stray cats wandering around the island, some joined us for breakfast :) &lt;img src=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;float:right;&quot; /&gt; After breakfast we went kayaking around the island for a few hours, stopping to swim and snorkel and play at the beach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kadie16/kadie16.github.io/master/assets/images/posts/phi-phi/kayak.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;center&gt; Kayaking &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After kayaking Sarah and I went and got pedicures for 150 baht (a little under $4). I regret not getting gel nails because it was only 400 baht and I ruined my toes the next day. We ended the night playing scrabble at another bar. At first we were playing in a little boat table thing, but there were a lot of bugs. I guess I was making a scene because one of the workers came over to give me some bug repelent hahaha.I won with a 56 point word “hack”. Actually we never recounted but I’m pretty sure I won :P.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kadie16/kadie16.github.io/master/assets/images/posts/phi-phi/nailPolish.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;center&gt; The Nail Salon &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kadie16/kadie16.github.io/master/assets/images/posts/phi-phi/nailSelfie.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;center&gt; Us at The Nail Salon &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kadie16/kadie16.github.io/master/assets/images/posts/phi-phi/sunset2.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;center&gt; Sunset Bar Again &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first two days on Phi Phi were amazing, but my last full day was by far my favorite! First, we returned to our breakfast spot for more thai pancakes and banana shakes. Our waitress was named Ooh. I got a hot coffee and I ended up asking to buy the spoon for a souvenier. Ooh seemed really confused about why I wanted the spoon but she laughed when I told her I liked it and let me buy it for 100 baht. I had a little cheat sheet to help me learn so basic thai words and Ooh helped me pronounce them. Hello sounds like “sah-wat-dee-ah” and thank you sounds like “khub-kan-kah”, I think. I don’t think I was doing it very well because Ooh seemed to be the only person who could understand me hahaha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kadie16/kadie16.github.io/master/assets/images/posts/phi-phi/breakfast.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;center&gt; Me waiting for my pancakes, Ooh in background &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kadie16/kadie16.github.io/master/assets/images/posts/phi-phi/thaiPancake.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;center&gt; Nom Nom Thai Pancake &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After breakfast we went to get massages. Sarah and I got one hour Thai massages with oil for 300 baht (a little under $9) and Ryan got a regular Thai massage. I really liked the oil. The thai massage was sometimes like a regular massage, and sometimes felt like the ladies were helping us stretch. I thought our massuses were really funny. They really liked Ryan. They kept saying “handsome boy, not handsome man” because he is 20. They were making some other lewd comments which I found hilarious but I think they started making Sarah and Ryan feel a little uncomfortable hahaha. At the end, I felt so good and so relaxed!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some shopping, we went back to the room to get ready for our cliff jumping and snorkeling tour! We had booked it the previous day for 600 baht (~ $18). This was by far the highlight of phi phi. I can’t think of any better way to spend $18.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kadie16/kadie16.github.io/master/assets/images/posts/phi-phi/preTour.JPG&quot; /&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;center&gt; The beginning of our Tour &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the beginning we made some friends: two other americans and a british girl named Emma. We got on a boat together and met our guide who said he was named Michael, but he may have made that up. Our first stop was monkey beach! There were atleast 30 monkeys there to greet us. Michael advised us not to bring anything that we didn’t want the monkeys to steal. The monkeys were very brave and would walk right up to people in the water to grab whatever food was in their hand. There is a video of me and Ryan feeding them pineapples and peanuts in the photostream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kadie16/kadie16.github.io/master/assets/images/posts/phi-phi/monkeys.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;center&gt; Monkeys &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt; 
&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kadie16/kadie16.github.io/master/assets/images/posts/phi-phi/monkeySelfie.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;center&gt; Trying to take selfies with monkeys &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next we went to go cliff jumping. While we were approaching the cliff we were going to jump off, we saw a pod of dolphins. It was magical. I love cliff jumping and at first I thought I would jump off the highest point, until I saw someone start climbing up and realized how small they looked compared to the rest of the rock! The one we ended up doing was the second highest, about 15 meters according to Michael. I think it was the highest I’ve ever done. We wanted to go again but we had to continue the tour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After everyone jumped, we headed to the famous Maya Bay, where the movie “The Beach” was filmed. I have no words for how breathtakingly gorgeous this place was. All I can say is that the whole time I was there I felt overwhelmed by it’s beauty. It was surreal, to say the least. Giant cliffs covered in lush, green trees towered over us as we walked to the other side of the island. 
&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kadie16/kadie16.github.io/master/assets/images/posts/phi-phi/mayaBaySelfie.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;center&gt; The other side &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt; 
Michael suggested we run through the forest and into the ocean because they do that in the movie, so I convinced Sarah, Ryan, and our friends to do it with me. Only I made it all the way into the end but it was still fun :D! Then I went and played a volley ball game on the beach that a russian guy taught us. There were 10 or 12 of us playing in a circle. None of us had ever met before, we were of different nationalities from all over the world, and we were playing a game together in the most beautiful place I have ever visited. If there has ever been a perfect moment in my life, that was it. I had a giant smile on my face the whole time. I am in awe just remembering it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kadie16/kadie16.github.io/master/assets/images/posts/phi-phi/mayaBay.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;center&gt; Maya Bay &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a short hour at Maya bay, we got back on the boat and went to snorkel on the other side where we had walked to. There were hundreds of coloful fish swimming around the reef, and we were still surrounded by the beautiful mountains. There were parrot fish, and a lot of other fish that I can’t remember the name of but I have only seen in aquariums. The water was the most beautiful, crystal clear emerald-teal shade, and it felt like a heated pool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;center&gt; Snorkeling behind Maya Bay &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the tour, we wathced the sunset and then jumped in the water one last time to drink some beers and swim with the green glowing plankton. Afterward, we made a plan with all of the friends we made to meet at banana bar at 9:30. We were super late because we were having dinner with Ooh, (who was still working!) but fortunately so was everyone else. We spent the rest of the night dancing and drinking and watching fire dancers at some bars on the beach. It was the best day ever :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kadie16/kadie16.github.io/master/assets/images/posts/phi-phi/emmeAndMe.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;center&gt;My New Friend Emma&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning I had one last breakfast with Ooh before running off to catch my ferry and flight to Sydney. I could write so much more but I only have so much time and so do you! I loved Koh Phi Phi so much, and I hope I will make it back there at least once this summer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;center&gt;Bye By Phi Phi!&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;** P.S. !! ** If you’re reading this, I would love for you to comment below!! &amp;lt;3&amp;lt;3&amp;lt;3&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://kadie16.github.io/koh-phi-phi/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kadie16.github.io/koh-phi-phi/</guid>
        
        <category>KohPhiPhi</category>
        
        
        <category>thailand</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>En Route</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kadie16/kadie16.github.io/master/assets/images/thumbnails/one.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Thumbnail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My passport was literally delivered to Emily and Morgan’s (my friends in LA) apartment yesterday. If you know me, that probably isn’t surprising. I ran into a bunch of passport issues a month before my trip but it made it just in time! So far I haven’t lost anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last two weeks have gone by so fast. I finished finals, visited friends in Santa Barbara, San Luis Obispo, Los Angeles, and my home in San Diego. Two weeks between school and my trip didn’t feel like enough time, but now I am so excited to be on my way. I have a short layover in seattle, and then a 17 hour flight to Singapore with a stop in Tokyo. When I arrive in Singapore, I will wait a few hours until my next flight to Thailand!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;packing-and-planning&quot;&gt;Packing and Planning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Saturday night, my friend Sarah told me she would be in Koh Phi Phi for a few days before I am leave for Australia. So, I found a plane ticket for the earliest possible flight to Krabi, Thailand, and from there I will take a ferry to Koh Phi Phi. Thailand is one of the places I want to go to the most, so I am stoked I get to so early in my trip! I definitely want to see Bangkok another time this summer. Plus, the fact that I am seeing a familiar face when I get there is making everything a lot less intimidating. Convienently, there was a problem with the payment for my flights to Australia, so all of the flights were booked except from Singapore to Australia. This ended up being perfect because now I am flying directly to Australia from Thailand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kadie16/kadie16.github.io/master/assets/images/posts/en-route%20/packed.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Too Much Stuff&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally I was going to bring all of this to Singapore. &lt;em&gt;Thank god&lt;/em&gt; I came to my senses. I went through all my stuff on my second to last night and decided to leave behind everything in and around the duffel bag on the left. I still feel overpacked and I seriously don’t know what the hell I was thinking when I packed the first time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still ended up checking my suitcase. When I got on the plane it wouldn’t fit in the overhead bin (lol oops). Thankfully the flight attendents were extremely nice and accomodating. They even helped me try to rearrange some things in my bag to see if it would fit. It was a pleasant experience and it’s easier to check it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kadie16/kadie16.github.io/master/assets/images/posts/en-route%20/suitcase.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bye bye my little suitcase&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;center&gt;bye bye little suitcase!&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;last-nights&quot;&gt;Last Nights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my second to last night in San Diego I went out in North Park with Thomy and Anthony, two of my best friends from my hometown. When we got home we stayed up until four in the morning reminiscing about all the funny things we did together in high shool. Like when Anthony taught me and Thomy how to drive, and other, more stupid stuff that I can not write about here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next night me and my dad walked and talked on the beach and later I cuddled and ate take out olive garden with my mom and sister.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last night I had more sleepover talk with Morgan, Emily, Jules, Josh, Nate, and Sean in LA :). We got take out sushi and a delicious breakfast delivered (brownie, pancakes, eggs, potatoes, toast, granola with fresh fruit and yogurt). Breakfast is my favorite meal. I so enjoyed visiting with all of them and they made me even more excited for my trip! I was so happy to be with everyone that I got a little sad because I would miss them, but it was sad happy because I am just thankful that I have so many people I love enough to miss :) It was the perfect way to spend my last nights :heart_eyes_cat:&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://kadie16.github.io/en-route/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kadie16.github.io/en-route/</guid>
        
        <category>airport</category>
        
        
        <category>united states</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Airports For Days</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I got to Singapore last night at 11:30 PM on the 3rd. Now it is about 10:00 am local time and I am on my plane to Krabi, Thailand :) I enjoy flying, so I didn’t find my flights to be that bad. I slept most of the way and I had fun exploring the Tokyo gift shops during my layoever in Japan. I thought the flight from Tokyo to Singapore was 2 hours until I asked the person next to me (it was 6 hours lol). He was an american who was living in Bali, and he showed me photos of his beautiful 3 story house made entirely out of Bamboo. The floors, blinds, doors, and furniture were all made from different kinds of bamboo. It looked like a giant tree house in the jungle. The upstairs area was completely open, so there weren’t any full walls, only blinds for when it rained. He said bees and bats and snakes all came in and out of the house as they pleased. His children attended a private school that was also completely made out of bamboo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since my flights were only 10 hours apart, I decided to just stay at the airport last night. I reserved a “nap room” at the Haven Lounge in the Changi Airport before I left the US. After I went through immigration, I asked someone where the lounge was. At first, he seemed super concerned and told me that there were no lounges outside immigration, but eventually he realized what I was talking about and told me to take the SkyTrain to “&lt;em&gt;foreign sounding word&lt;/em&gt; tree”. So I got on the SkyTrain and rode it back and forth once, looking for a stop with the word tree in it, until I realized he was probably actually saying “terminal three”. I wandered around some more and eventually found the lounge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I slept in the nap room until 6:30, and then I packed my things and got a key to use a shower room. The shower had three showerheads, and when I leaned inside to turn it on, it was set to the one that happened to be pointed outside of the shower, directly at my face. So a huge stream of water started spraying straight to my face hahaha. I screamed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I almost went to have breakfast at McDonalds until I asked where I could fill up my water bottle and realized the lounge had free snacks. I had a nice breakfast of toast, cereal, two apples, and a cappucino before I left to catch my flight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Singapore Changi Airport is really beautiful. There are gardens and art installations and shops everywhere. I stepped outside to take a photo and feel the weather and I started sweating within a minute. I didn’t get the photo because I’m still figuring out the go pro lol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this airport, you don’t have to go through security until you reach your gate. It was nice because there were only three people in front of me in the line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kadie16/kadie16.github.io/master/assets/images/posts/airport-life/SG4.JPG&quot; /&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;center&gt; Leaving Singapore &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I get to Krabi, I am taking a bus to a resturaunt travel agency thing, then a shuttle to the dock, and then a ferry to koh phi phi, where Sarah and Ryan will be waiting for me :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kadie16/kadie16.github.io/master/assets/images/posts/airport-life/KBV.JPG&quot; /&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;center&gt; Landing in Krabi, Thailand &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://kadie16.github.io/airport-life/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kadie16.github.io/airport-life/</guid>
        
        <category>airport</category>
        
        
        <category>singapore</category>
        
        <category>japan</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
